Welcome back.
잘 돌아왔어요
So hopefully you are still impressed by the GPT four mini results.
GPT 4 미니 결과에 여전히 감동하셨길 바라요
The frontier model coming in strong at just shy of $80 and with 52% hits just going above the 50% mark
프런티어 모델은 80달러로 큰 인기를 끌었고 조회 수가 52%로 50%를 넘어섰습니다 녹색
in terms of the number of green dots and a nice chart there.
점 수와 멋진 차트 덕분이죠
But the time has come for us to now run against its bigger cousin, big GPT four.
하지만 이제 더 큰 사촌 격인 GPT 4와 겨룰 때가 됐죠
Oh, I just did.
방금 했어요
I did want to mention that, uh, do be aware that at this point, uh, when we're talking about these
말씀드리고 싶은 건 이 시점에서 우리가 이런 종류의 오류 숫자에
kinds of error numbers, the error is already, uh, reasonably low.
대해 얘기할 때 오류는 이미 꽤 낮다는 거예요
You think about the actual prices of products.
제품의 실제 가격을 생각해 보세요
They do vary.
다양하죠
There is volatility baked into prices.
가격에 변동이 있어요
There are sales.
세일 중이에요
There's there's big swings when you come to things like the prices of a wheel or the price of a laptop.
바퀴나 노트북 가격 같은 건 큰 반전이 있어요
No doubt they vary quite considerably from different sites and different, uh, Stores, so there is
장소와 스토어마다 제각각인 건 분명합니다 그러니 이 질문에는 자연스러운
some natural error built into this question anyway.
오류가 내재돼 있죠
So we're certainly not expecting to to come down to small numbers.
그래서 소규모로 줄어들 거라고 기대하진 않아요
So from that point of view, recognize that every dollar improvement we get at this point is a is a
그런 관점에서 현재 1달러씩 개선될 때마다 그 자체로 get up
victory in its own right.
승리예요
We're going to be squeezing juice if we can, but don't expect a big change now.
가능하면 주스를 짜겠지만 큰 변화는 기대하지 마세요
We are now at a point where this is already super impressive and far ahead of any of the traditional
지금까지의 기술로는 이미 놀라운 수준이에요 기존의 머신 러닝 기술보다
machine learning techniques.
훨씬 앞섰죠
Um, so, uh, the next thing to do, of course, is to unveil the bigger cousin, GPT four.
다음 단계는 물론 더 큰 사촌 격인 GPT 4를 공개하는 거죠
Oh, here is the same type of function again, the function that we'll be passing to our test program.
여기 같은 형식의 함수가 또 있네요 테스트 프로그램에 통과시킬 함수죠
Uh, it's of course calling OpenAI ChatGPT completions dot create.
OpenAI 챗GPT완료 .Create라고 부르고요
We're using the GPT four model as of August the 6th, which is very recent.
8월 6일 기준으로 GPT 4 모델을 사용하고 있어요 아주 최근이죠
Um, passing in messages, passing in the seed and using the same way of getting back the results.
메시지를 전달하고 씨앗을 전달하고 같은 방법으로 결과를 얻는 거죠
It's worth mentioning this is now going to cost a little bit more.
미리 말씀드리자면 비트가 좀 더 들 거예요
It costs somewhere between $0.10 and $0.20 for me to run this across 250 points.
0달러 정도 해요 10달러와 0달러요 250점짜리 시험에 20점요
Um, so, um, yeah, I mean, it's not going to break the bank, but you might want to think twice
네, 돈이 많이 들진 않겠지만 100번씩 방송하기 전에
before running this a hundred times.
다시 생각해 보세요
Uh, so I do urge you to at least try it once.
그러니까 적어도 한 번은 시도해 보세요
It's it's great fun.
정말 재미있어요
Um, but, yeah, it doesn't it doesn't necessarily need to be run a lot of times.
하지만 자주 실행할 필요는 없어요
I also want to mention that you might wonder why I'm not trying to run this against oh one.
제가 왜 이걸 O1에 대항해 실행하지 않는지 궁금하실 수도 있어요
Uh, so the kind of problems are that oh one is designed for.
오 원의 용도는 이런 문제들이었어요
Ah, more the problems where there is deeper thinking required, a multi-step thought process and challenging.
더 깊이 있는 사고가 필요한 문제입니다 다단계 사고 과정으로 어려운 문제들이죠
And that doesn't really lend itself to the problem that we're tackling here.
그건 우리가 다루는 문제와 맞지 않아요
Um, it would also be slower and more expensive and for no good reason.
더 느리고 더 비싸겠죠 아무 이유 없이요
We're not trying to solve, uh, math puzzles.
수학 퍼즐을 푸는 게 아니에요
We're just trying to have the most likely next guess of a price based on worldly knowledge.
세속적인 지식을 바탕으로 가격을 가장 잘 추측해 보려고요
So GPT four frontier should be our best shot.
GPT 4 프런티어가 가장 좋은 기회예요
Um.
네
And I have, of course, already run it.
물론 이미 실행해봤죠
Uh, so it's a little bit slower than GPT four mini.
GPT 4 미니 비트보다 조금 느린데요
Just a little bit.
비트 주세요
But I think you should run it yourself and you'll enjoy it.
하지만 직접 운영해 보면 재미있을 거예요
And here are the results I get.
Get it 결과가 나왔어요
Um, so there's a lot of greens, but there's lots of reds as well.
녹색도 많고 빨간색도 많아요
So it's quite a variety here.
꽤 다양하네요
Um, no doubt you're betting.
내기하는 거 맞죠?
And here are the results.
결과가 나왔어요
So the bottom line is it is better.
결론은 이게 더 낫다는 거죠
It is improved it for sure.
확실히 좋아졌네요
It's gone from about 80 to about 76.
80에서 76으로 떨어졌어요
And the hits from 52 to 58.
52점부터 58점까지 점수를 올렸죠
Uh, green dots.
초록색 점요
It's not a massive change.
큰 변화는 아니에요
You may have expected more going from mini to GPT four, but remember GPT four mini is really good.
미니에서 4급 GPT로 발전할 거라고 기대하셨겠지만 4급 GPT 미니는 정말 좋은 차예요
And despite the fact that it's a much cheaper model, it has much the very similar smarts to GPT four
훨씬 저렴한 모델임에도 불구하고 GPT 40과 매우 비슷한 스마트함을 갖추고
zero.
있죠
Um, so I would say, first of all, it is to be celebrated that we've come down by by $6 by $4.
우선 축하할 일이 있어요 6달러 4달러 줄었어요
Sorry.
미안해요
Uh, but but also that, um, we can already assume that GPT four mini has done very well indeed.
하지만 이미 GPT 4 미니는 아주 잘 달리고 있다고 볼 수 있죠
Um, so, um.
그래서 말인데요
Yeah, this is this is, uh, this is the results.
네, 이게 결과예요
It looks visually very impressive.
시각적으로 아주 인상적이에요
The the I mean, compare it to humanity.
인간적인 것과 비교해 보세요
Uh, at the end of this lecture, I think we'll end by going back and embarrassingly looking at the
강의를 마무리하기 전에 부끄럽지만 도표를 다시 한번
chart one more time, uh, comparing it to what frontier models are able to achieve.
보면서 선구자 모델의 성과를 비교해 보도록 하죠
Uh, but this does give you a good sense.
하지만 이걸 보면 감이 오죠
Okay.
네
And then, of course, we do have one more frontier model that perhaps we should unveil, which is Claude
그리고 아직 공개하지 않은 개척지 모델이 하나 더 있는데 바로 클로드
3.5 sonnet.
3이에요 5 소네트요
Um, which is the strongest, uh, model from anthropic And, um, you recognize, I hope the structure.
인류학에서 가장 강력한 모델이죠 구조도 알아보시겠죠?
Uh, Claude messages create uh, again.
클로드 메시지가 다시 만들어요
Now, with in the case of Claude, you can't pass in a seed.
클로드의 경우에는 씨앗을 전달할 수 없어요
It doesn't take that.
그런 게 아니에요
So the results will be different each time.
매번 결과가 다를 거예요
But I've just gone with the first run I've done in here, and that's what we'll have as, as the, uh,
하지만 전 여기서 처음 실행한 걸 사용했어요 그게 우리
the, uh, the results for, for our purposes.
목적을 위한 결과로 나올 거예요
And I guess I'll probably, uh, replicate and save this notebook.
이 공책도 복사해서 보관할 거예요
So we have it for, for posterity.
후세를 위해 남겨뒀어요
Uh, so time for Claude starts with a couple of reds, then a sea of greens.
클로드는 빨강 두어 개로 시작해서 초록 바다를 칠해요
And I will get us straight to some outcomes.
Get in get 결과로 바로 넘어가죠
So here's the results from Claude.
클로드가 결과를 보냈어요
Interestingly, Claude actually does a little bit worse.
흥미롭게도 클로드는 더 심한 비트를 입었어요
Uh, it's, uh, um, uh, worse, in fact, than GPT four mini in this task, and worse also than the
이번 작업은 GPT 4 미니보다도 못한 것 같아요 랜덤 숲보다도 못한 것 같아요
Of course, again, Random Forest had the benefit of all of its training data 400,000 training data.
랜덤 포레스트는 훈련 데이터의 혜택을 많이 받았어요 400,000 훈련 데이터요
So it's a very different kind of of of test.
아주 색다른 테스트예요
And you can see one of the reasons for that is that you can tell from this axis that it has made some
그 이유 중 하나는 이 축을 보면 예측을 할 수 있기 때문이죠
We can't quite see it because it's going to be a little tiny red dot, but it made some massively outsized
아주 작은 빨간 점이라 잘 보이진 않지만 엄청난 예측을 했어요
prediction, although that will of course been spread out across everything.
물론 모든 곳에 퍼지겠지만요
So it wouldn't have made a huge difference.
큰 차이는 없었을 거예요
But still, uh, one guess would have been like way, way too high and will have certainly, uh, certainly
하지만 그래도 너무 높았을 가능성이 있어요 그래서 결과물이 약간 비뚤어졌을
made its results be a bit distorted.
거예요
Let's see if we can spy that from scanning through here.
여기를 스캔해서 볼 수 있는지 보죠
Where did it go so wrong?
어디서부터 잘못된 걸까요?
Here it is.
여기 있네요
G technology G speed ES pro high performance.
G테크놀로지 G스피드 ES 프로 고성능이죠
So this thing which actually cost $495.95.
이 기계는 495달러예요 95살요
It guest was $4,999 and 99.
손님은 4,999달러 99센트였어요
So it was a very outsized guest there that introduced 4500 error.
4500 오류를 도입한 건 초대형 게스트였어요
Now, obviously, that that error in itself won't distort things too much because it gets averaged out
그 오류 자체는 크게 왜곡되지 않아요 250개의 데이터
across the 250 data points.
포인트 평균이 나오니까요
But it's an example of one of the things that pushed it into the worst camp.
하지만 최악의 캠프로 내몰린 좋은 예죠
So those are the results from Claude.
클로드가 결과를 보냈어요
Uh, still has a nice diagram here, but didn't quite measure up in this with this particular challenge,
여기 도표가 있지만 이번 과제에서는 기대에 못 미쳤어요 프런티어
uh, to GPT four or GPT four at the frontier was the winner of this challenge.
GPT4가 이번 과제의 우승자였죠
You'll remember Claude won when it came to the coding performance challenge, by a way, a big, big
클로드가 코딩 성능 과제에서 우승한 거 기억하시죠? 엄청난 마진을 기록했어요
Uh, but in this case, for this particular challenge, our winner is Claude.
하지만 이번 게임의 승자는 클로드예요
Uh, is sorry, is GPT four at the frontier.
죄송합니다, GPT 4가 프런티어에 있어요
And as I promised, I will leave you by one more look at the.
약속드린 대로 한 번만 더 보고 갈게요
At this human's feeble attempt.
인간의 미약한 시도에 말이죠
Take a look at the nice, elegant diagram here with a number of green dots with GPT four guessing close
GPT 4로 표시된 초록색 점들이 멋진 도표를 보여줍니다 홈런에
to the to a home run.
가까운 수치죠
And now compare that with the performance of the resident human in the room.
이제 이 결과를 방에 있는 사람의 결과와 비교해 보죠
Uh, and this was my chart.
이건 제 차트예요
That I don't want to look at that ever again.
다시는 보고 싶지 않아요
Uh, all right.
알았어요
Anyway, I hope that this was a, uh, educational exercise for you.
어쨌든, 이게 당신에게 교육적인 경험이 됐길 바라요
And you see how you would do, uh, experiments like this with your own business problems.
본인 사업 문제로 이런 실험을 어떻게 하는지 아시겠죠
Please do.
그러세요
Now, come replicate this.
이제 이걸 따라 해 보세요
Play around with this, uh, you'll find, particularly with Claude, of course, that you won't get
이것저것 해 보면 특히 클로드에게서는 씨앗이 없기 때문에 같은
the same results because there's no seed.
결과를 얻지 못해요 get it
Um, but you will get some something different and see how it performs.
Get it로 색다른 걸 만들어 성능을 보는 거죠
Maybe you'll get better results than me.
어쩌면 나보다 더 좋은 결과를 낼지도 모르죠 get it get it get it
Uh, but I will see you to wrap up with some more slides.
마무리할 때는 슬라이드를 더 보여드릴게요